

Age: 37

Website: www.davelee.de

Degree: PhD in Computing Science

JAVA	100%
SPRING FRAMEWORK (SPRING BOOT, DATA ETC.)	90%
CI/CD DEVOPS (JENKINS, MAVEN,)	95%

WEB DEVELOPMENT (HTML, PHP/MYSQL, CSS, ANGULAR)	95%
PROJECT MANAGEMENT TOOLS (E.G. JIRA, ASANA)	100%
CLOUD COMPUTING (AWS)	80%

Summary

O DAVID A J LEE

Experienced software developer, architect and product owner with +15 years of experience in software development from requirements through an initial concept and minimum viable products to a great product for the customer. Passionate about developing others to reach their potential through coaching and leadership roles.

- · British & German Nationality
- Languages: English (Native Speaker) & German (Fluent)
- · Current Location: Berlin, Germany
- Get in contact with me through the contact formular.

Education

CERTIFIED PROFESSIONAL SOFTWARE ARCHITECT (FOUNDATION LEVEL)

2015

Hamburg, Germany

Topics included: foundations of software architectures, components/building blocks, interfaces, architectural goals, quality goals and tools.

DOCTOR OF PHILOSOPHY IN COMPUTING

2006 - 2010

The Robert Gordon University, Aberdeen, Scotland

Thesis title: Hybrid Algorithms for Distributed Constraint Satisfaction. In my doctoral research, I investigated and developed hybrid algorithms for Distributed Constraint Satisfaction, combining the convergence abilities of local search with the completeness of backtracking. This has led to the development of new algorithms for Distributed Constraint Satisfaction including PenDHyb, Multi-Hyb and Multi-HDCS.

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE WITH 1ST CLASS HONOURS IN COMPUTING FOR BUSINESS AND E-COMMERCE

2002 - 2006

The Robert Gordon University, Aberdeen, Scotland

This degree combined a standard Computing Science degree with several business modules such as Marketing, Accounting and Change Management particularly focused on an E-Commerce context.

Professional Experience

O INTERIM TEAM LEAD PRODUCT MANAGEMENT

January 2022 - Present

myToys.de GmbH, Berlin, Germany

- People Leadership responsibilites for team of Product Managers.
- Responsible for co-ordinating roadmaps between product teams.

SENIOR PRODUCT MANAGER

July 2020 - Present

myToys.de GmbH, Berlin, Germany

- Responsible for search, checkout and product data systems.
- Coaching other product managers and product owners.

PRODUCT MANAGER

February 2018 - June 2020

myToys.de GmbH, Berlin, Germany

- Responsible for the development of Content Management System.
- Customer-centric product development and benchmarking.

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

July 2014 - January 2018

myToys.de GmbH, Berlin, Germany

- 40% software development of prototypes and techniques.
- 30% technical leadership of projects
- 30% future architecture (vision, technical roadmap, standards)

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

August 2010 - June 2014

myToys.de GmbH, Berlin, Germany

- · Backend-based Java developer
- Java + Spring Server/Client System with REST for Coupons including migration of 30 million codes
- Java + Spring Job Portal for recruitment.